Register of the United States National Student Association International Commission records
Hoover Institution Archives
- SUBJECT FILE OF ORGANIZATIONS, 1946-1966
  - War Resisters League, undated
  - Washington Center for Metropolitan Studies, 1962
  - Washington Friends Seminar Program, 1964
  - Washington Human Rights Project, 1963-1964
  - Washington Seminar on International Affairs, 1962
  - West African Student Union, 1954, 1956
  - Western College Association, 1948
  - Western Interstate Commission for Higher Education, 1963-1965
  - Western Personnel Institute, 1954-1963
  - Western Psychological Association, 1960
  - Western Regional Student Program, 1964-1965
  - Whitney Museum of American Art, 1965
  - William Morriss Agency, 1962
  - Williamsburg International Assembly, 1956, 1966
  - Wisconsin Association of Student Councils, 1963
  - Wisconsin Student Association, 1965
  - Women's International League for Peace and Freedom, 1964
  - Women's League for Israel, Inc., 1965
  - Women Strike for Peace, 1962
  - Woodrow Wilson Foundation, 1950-1958
  - Woolworth (F.W.) Company, 1960-1961
  - Worker (The), 1965
  - Workmen Circle, 1964
  - World, 1952-1953
  - World Affairs Center for the United States, 1957-1960
  - World Assembly of Youth, 1947-1956
  - Washington Seminar, 1952-1953 (Box 298)
  - World Assembly of Youth, 1956-1965
  - World Association of World Federalists, 1959-1961
  - World Confederation of Organizations of the Teaching Profession, 1959, 1962
  - World Council of Churches, 1949, 1954-1955
  - World Federation of Democatic Youth, 1946-1959
  - World Federation of Democratic Youth, 1959-1963 (Box 299)
  - World Peace Foundation, 1957, 1960
  - World Peace Study Mission, 1964
  - World Refugee Year, 1959-1960
  - World Student Christian Federation, 1949-1963
  - World Student Relief, 1947-1952
  - World Student Service Fund, 1947-1948
  - World Student Service Fund, 1947-1951 (Box 300)
  - World Student Service Fund, 1952-1953 (Box 301)
  - World Union of Jewish Students, undated
  - World University, 1951
  - World University Service
    - Constitution, by-laws, and history
    - International, 1956-1964
    - International, Minutes, 1950-1959 (Box 302)
    - Britain, 1955-1961
    - Canada, 1955-1961 (Box 303)
    - Germany, 1955-1957
    - Ghana, 1956-1957
    - Helsinki, 1954-1956
    - India, 1955-1957
    - Japan, 1954-1955
    - Latin America, 1956
    - Poona (India), 1955-1956
    - Spain, 1955-1956
    - United States (Box 304)
      - General, 1952-1955
      - Correspondence, 1947-1955
      - Correspondence, 1955-1960 (Box 305)
      - Correspondence, 1960-1967 (Box 306)
      - Finance Committee, 1954-1965
      - General Committee and Board of Trustees, 1953-1957
      - General Committee and Board of Trustees, 1957-1961 (Box 307)
      - General Committee and Board of Trustees, 1961-1967 (Box 308)
      - News sheets and bulletins, 1960-1965
      - Publicity, 1953-1954
      - Regional reports, 1954-1964
  - World University Service and International Union of Students, 1954-1956 (Box 309)
  - World Veterans Association, 1956-1957
  - Worldwide Fast for Peace, 1963
  - Yale Center for the Study of Alcoholism, 1962
  - Young Adult Council (Box 309)
    - Correspondence, 1948-1963
    - History, membership, by-laws, 1951-1961
    - Educational Activities, 1952
    - Reports, 1951-1955
    - Reports, 1955-1960 (Box 310)
    - Reports, 1960-1964 (Box 311)
    - U.S. National Student Association, 1951-1954
    - U.S. National Student Association, 1951, 1957-1963 (Box 312)
    - World Assembly of Youth, 1951-1959
  - Young Christian Students, 1955-1961
  - Young Democratic Clubs of America, 1951-1961
  - Young Men's Christian Association, 1960
  - Young People's Socialist League, 1960
  - Young Republican National Federation, 1957-1960
  - Young World Federalists, 1954, 1956
  - Zanzibar Youths and Students Union, 1964
  - Zimbabwe African People's Union (Rhodesia), 1966-1967
  - Zimbabwe Student Union in Americas, 1966-1967
- PHOTOGRAPHS (Envelopes A-E, mF-mG)
  Includes 692 prints and 27 negatives in 7 envelopes.
- INCREMENTAL MATERIALS
  - National Student Association
    - Miscellaneous (Box 313)
    - Financial Reports, 1951-1965
    - Almanac General (Box 314)
    - Executive Committee, 1948-1949
    - Student Congresses 16th
    - Student Congresses 17th
  - Coordinating Secretariat File
    - Conferences and Seminars, 1968
    - International Student Seminars, 14th, 1963
  - International Union of Students
    - Background and Historical Data
    - Meetings, World Student Congresses, 8th
    - Meetings, World Student Congresses, 7th
  - Office File
    - National Supervisory Board
  - 9th International Student Relation Seminar, Harald Bakken (Box 315)
  - 12th International Student Relation Seminar
    - Africa, Rick Stearns
    - Introductory materials (Box 316)
    - Sub-Saharan Africa, Richard Stearns
    - Week Two, International Relations, Rick Stearns
    - Week Three, Latin America, Rick Stearns
    - Sixth Week, Rick Stearns
  - 13th International Student Relation Seminar
    - Relating to Middle East (Box 317)
    - Week Seven, Asia, Rich Stearns
  - National Unions of Students
    - Geographical File, Canada
    - Geographical File, Kuwait
    - Geographical File, Palestine
  - Subject File of Organizations
    - Joint Committee for Student Action
    - Students for Democratic Action
    - Student League for Industrial Democracy
  - Articles (Box 318)
    - Five Articles about International Student Conferences and the International Union of Students
    - The Spencer Three Year Plan for the Student Movement in the Dominican Republic
    - Latin America; the Need for Strengthening Student Political Groups in the Multi-University Country Situation
    - Draft - Memorandum on International Programming
    - Regarding USNSA
    - International Student Organizations
    - Middle East & North African Student Affairs
    - Section A - Historical Development and Present Activities of Latin American Student Groups
    - Political Background Project - Panama
    - Christian Democratic Youth Movements in Latin America: Theory and Practice
    - Political Background Project - The Rise of the Latin American Left
    - Indonesia-Malaysia, Problems and Prospects
    - Student Politics in Latin America
  - Sound Recordings, 1954-1963
    Titles taken directly from tape labels.
    - USNSA (Box 319)
    - The Middle East - Bob Williams, 1954 August 4
    - East European Student Movement, 1954 July 28
    - USNSA, 1954 July 20
    - WFPV - Ed Garvy Interview, 1961 September 25
    - Scandinavia-Italy, 1954 July 26
    - World Union of Jewish Students, World Student Christian Federation, Pax Romana, 1954
    - International Student Seminar, Dartmouth, 1962 June 25
    - Northrop Auditorium Sit-in Reel #2
    - USNSA Teams to India - F. Fisher, 1954 July 29
    - Hans B. - Southwest Africa
    - Problem Papers on Latin America, 1954 July 29
    - International Student Seminar, Dartmouth, 1962 June 21-22
    - Latin America I - HJR
    - The Helsinki WUS Assembly, 1955 (Box 320)
    - The Foreign Student
    - International Student Seminar, Dartmouth, 1962 June 24-25
    - Algeuan Tops with Emmerson - Part I
    - International Student Seminar, Dartmouth, 1962 June 19
    - Cases Publications; Problem Papers
    - Sen Renaulo - Reel II
    - Testimony at HUAC, 1960 May
    - France and Istanbul
    - Africa - W. Brown; Israel - S. Gottlieb, 1954
    - ISRS- General Discussion of International Relations, 1954 July 14
    - Latin America II, HJR, 1954 February 29
    - Luis Alberto Reyes #3-4
    - Pentzer-Simons, 1954 (Box 321)
    - YAC
    - Fact and Fiction in World Youth Festivals
    - Academic Freedom I & II
    - NUS, Austria - Brothers in the West, 1963
    - Parody of Session
    - College News Conference, 1958 April 27
    - ISRS Session, 1954 July 15
    - John Simons, History of IUS, pt. I, "The Founding of IUS"
    - Burma-Philippines, Frank Fisher, 1954 July 30
    - Deatyer on Student Exchange, pt. II and Simons, pt. II
    - Ronald Oliver, BNUS
    - USNSA Northrop Auditorium, sit in #2 (Box 322)
    - Italy, Spain, and Yugoslavia
    - International Student Seminar, Dartmouth, 1962 June 19-20
    - Speech of Welcome 1955 Seminar
    - Clifford Orientation, 1960 October 12
    - For Mr. Gable: Report on Nigeria